Guide to the Freewater Production Films and Records, 1967-2003 and undated UA.09.13.0005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Freewater Productions Films: 1989, 35 items
  - All Hallow's Eve (1989)
    - Negative, 16mm, co., reel 1 of 1, 200 ft. (Box 9)
      From container: Color Negative Original.
    - Negative, 16mm, co., reel 1 of 1, 140 ft. (Box 9)
      From container: Negative A-Roll.
    - Negative, 16mm, co., reel 1 of 1, 140 ft. (Box 9)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 200 ft. (Box 9)
      From container: Sound mix.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., co., reel 1 of 2, 250 ft. (Box 9)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., co., reel 2 of 2, 150 ft. (Box 9)
  - Beyond Lassos (1989)
    Directed by Douglass Mankoff. From container: Douglass Mankoff follows the life of young rodeo cowboy and student Jeff Miller in this documentary.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., b&w, reel 1 of 1, 625 ft. (Box 9)
  - [Duke University Union Promo] (1989)
    Cue Sheet moved to Documentation series.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 4, 250 ft. (Box 10)
      From container: A-B S/T Negative.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 2 of 4, 175 ft. (Box 10)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 3 of 4, 175 ft. (Box 10)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 4 of 4, 175 ft. (Box 10)
  - Easy Answers (1989)
    Directed by Adam Rogers. From container: A very ambitious piece about a boy writing a paper who goes back in time to visit South Africa during the Sixties.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 1000 ft. (Box 9)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 825 ft. (Box 9)
      From container: Sound mix; Degaussed.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 2, 850 ft. (Box 9)
      From container: A/B Roll.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reel 2 of 2, 850 ft. (Box 9)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 150 ft. (Box 9)
      From container: One-lite Ekta-89 work print.
    - Betacam SP, b&w, 24 min. (Box 35)
      Tape also includes: Muffin Man.
  - Old Man (1989)
    Directed by Jack Angelo.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 2, 200 ft. (Box 10)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 2 of 2, 200 ft. (Box 10)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 300 ft. (Box 10)
      From container: Sound Roll.
      Mixing Instructions moved to Documentation series.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 2, 180 ft. (Box 10)
      From container: ECN Negative A-Roll Tail.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 2 of 2, 180 ft. (Box 10)
      From container: ECN Negative B-Roll Tail.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 200 ft. (Box 10)
      From container: Cemetary scenes, hospital scenes (bedroom).
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 180 ft. (Box 10)
      From container: Hospital corridor, garage scenes.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 150 ft. (Box 10)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 140 ft. (Box 10)
      From container: Work Print Edit.
    - Unexposed, 16mm, sd., reel 1 of 1, 160 ft. (Box 10)
      [Sound only.]
  - Perchance to Dream (1989)
    Directed by Henry Lee.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., co., reel 1 of 1, 600 ft. (Box 10)
      Director's Notes on splicing moved to Documentation series.
  - Untitled (1989)
    Directed by Robeson.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 4, 600 ft. (Box 11)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 2 of 4, 80 ft. (Box 11)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 3 of 4, 350 ft. (Box 11)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 4 of 4, 280 ft. (Box 11)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., co., reel 1 of 1, 550 ft. (Box 11)
      From container: Work Print; No sound (shot for sync); Interview of a couple.
  - Untitled films (1989)
    - Negative, 16mm, co., reel 1 of 1, 100 ft. (Box 11)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 400 ft. (Box 11)
      From reel: Bathroom humor.
- Freewater Productions Films: 1990, 38 boxes
  Contains films made in 1990.
  - [Darius] (1990)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 320 ft. (Box 14)
  - Devil's Quarters (1990)
    Directed by Chris Speck.
    - Negative, 16mm, reels 1-3 of 3, 550 ft. (Box 11)
      Includes 3 reels of varying sizes. From container: ECN Original and Trims.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 300 ft. (Box 11)
      From container: Sound.
      Instructions Sheet moved to Documentation series.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, co., reel 1 of 3, 25 ft. (Box 11)
      From container: Color Positive Work Print CRI-4.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, co., reel 2 of 3, 100 ft. (Box 11)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, co., reel 3 of 3, 15 ft. (Box 11)
  - Dinner Date (1990)
    - Negative, 16mm, co., reel 1 of 1, 110 ft. (Box 11)
    - Negative, 16mm, co., reel 1 of 1, 100 ft. (Box 11)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, co., reel 1 of 1, 125 ft. (Box 11)
      From container: Color Positive Workprint.
  - Duke University Union Promo (1990)
    Directed by Sam Ware.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 9, 300 ft. (Box 12)
      From container: Trims and Outtakes.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 2 of 9, 300 ft. (Box 12)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reels 3-7 of 9, 500 ft. (Box 12)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 8 of 9, 150 ft. (Box 12)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 9 of 9, 150 ft. (Box 12)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 2, 60 ft. (Box 12)
      From container: EKTA Workprint.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reel 2 of 2, 60 ft. (Box 12)
  - [Freewater Productions Films Workshop Reel] (1990)
    - Negative, 16mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 2, 380 ft. (Box 13)
      From container: A-Roll.
    - Negative, 16mm, si., b&w, reel 2 of 2, 380 ft. (Box 13)
      From container: B-Roll.
    - Negative, 16mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, 400 ft. (Box 13)
      From container: B-Wind and Optional Soundtrack.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 360 ft. (Box 13)
      From container: Sound Mix.
    - Optical Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 330 ft. (Box 13)
      From container: Optical Sound Track.
  - [Klink] (1990)
    - Negative, 16mm, si., co., reel 1 of 1, 220 ft. (Box 14)
  - Komedy U (1990)
    Directed by Langdon Steve and Fox Buckley. From container: Not a Freewater Production.
    Commercial film for colleges, featuring TV commercials, NBA games, etc. Trailer for the film Mermaids at end of reel. Stand-up comedy.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., co., reel 1 of 2, 700 ft. (Box 12)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., co., reel 2 of 2, 700 ft. (Box 12)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 260 ft. (Box 12)
  - Southern Culture on the Skids (1990)
    Directed by Bill Hayes and Michael G. Mitchell.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 100 ft. (Box 12)
    - Reversal Original, 16mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, 440 ft. (Box 12)
      From container: Original.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 800 ft. (Box 12)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 400 ft. (Box 12)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 110 ft. (Box 12)
  - Two Sticks for Fire (1990)
    Directed by Michael Mitchell and George Richman. Music by Darren Redlick.
    - Negative, 16mm, sd., co., reel 1 of 2, 650 ft. (Box 13)
      From container: I-Negative S/T.
    - Negative, 16mm, sd., co., reel 2 of 2, 600 ft. (Box 13)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 700 ft. (Box 13)
      From container: Sound Effects.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 700 ft. (Box 13)
      From container: Dialogue.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 600 ft. (Box 13)
      From container: Music.
    - VHS, 120 min. (Box 37)
  - Untitled (1990)
    Directed by Mike Mitchell.
    - Betacam SP, 34 min. (Box 35)
      From Container: 16mm transfer, April 25, 1990.
- Freewater Productions Films: 1991, 28 items
  Contains films made in 1991.
  - Brady Bunch (1991)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 120 ft. (Box 14)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 120 ft. (Box 14)
      From container: Work Print.
  - Day-4-Nite (1991)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, si., b&w, reel 1 of 1, 125 ft. (Box 14)
      From container: Tests.
  - Gerhart Interview (1991)
    Directed by Jensen and Madden.
    - Betacam SP, tapes 1-7 of 7, 210 min. (Box 37)
  - Pizza King (1991)
    Directed by Max Day. Alternates between interview and narrative formats.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 9, 800 ft. (Box 15)
      From container: ECN Original, Heads, Trims.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 2 of 9, 350 ft. (Box 15)
    - Negative, 16mm, reels 3-9 of 9, 1200 ft. (Box 15)
      Includes 7 reels of varying sizes. From container: ECN.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 3, 920 ft. (Box 15)
      From container: Heads.
      Timing Chart moved to Documentation series.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 2 of 3, 920 ft. (Box 15)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 3 of 3, 920 ft. (Box 15)
      From container: B Wind S/T.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 380 ft. (Box 15)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 450 ft. (Box 15)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 1200 ft. (Box 15)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 320 ft. (Box 15)
    - Betacam SP, 25 min. (Box 35)
      Tape also includes: The Legend of the Herring, Duet/Biology.
  - The Chase (1991)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 140 ft. (Box 14)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, co., reel 1 of 2, 140 ft. (Box 14)
      Reel also includes: Kung Fu.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, co., reel 2 of 2, 140 ft. (Box 14)
  - Weydig (1991)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 2, 550 ft. (Box 14)
      From container: Work Print. No sound (shot for sync).
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reel 2 of 2, 350 ft. (Box 14)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 1200 ft. (Box 14)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 1500 ft. (Box 14)
      From container: Edited Work Print.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 1500 ft. (Box 14)
- Freewater Productions Films: 1992, 37 items
  Contains films made in 1992.
  - Ceci N'est Pas un Film (1992)
    Directed by Adam Joyce. From container: A film about a guy making a film.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 4, 800 ft. (Box 16)
      Timing Charts moved to Documentation series.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 2 of 4, 800 ft. (Box 16)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 3 of 4, 800 ft. (Box 16)
      From container: Heads / Picture Reel.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 4 of 4, 800 ft. (Box 16)
      From container: B-Wind S/T.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 6, 275 ft. (Box 16)
    - Negative, 16mm, reels 2-6 of 6, 1000 ft. (Box 16)
      Includes 5 reels of varying sizes. From container: ECN Original, Heads, Trims.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 725 ft. (Box 16)
  - Comedy Spot (1992)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 140 ft. (Box 17)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 110 ft. (Box 17)
  - Duke Open '93 (1992)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., co., reel 1 of 1, 300 ft. (Box 17)
      From container: Checkprint.
  - Duke University Union Promo (1992)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 6, 350 ft. (Box 17)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 2 of 6, 150 ft. (Box 17)
      From container: Tail Original ECN.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reels 3-6 of 6, 350 ft. (Box 17)
      Includes 4 reels of varying sizes. From container: ECN.
  - The Happy Stone and the Meaning of Life (1992)
    Directed by Steve Reissner.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 375 ft. (Box 17)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 375 ft. (Box 18)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 6, 475 ft. (Box 18)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 2 of 6, 250 ft. (Box 18)
    - Negative, 16mm, reels 3-5 of 6, 725 ft. (Box 18)
      Includes 3 reels of varying sizes. From container: ECN.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 6 of 6, 1300 ft. (Box 18)
      From container: ECN Originals.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 250 ft. (Box 17)
      From container: Voiceovers.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 250 ft. (Box 18)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., co., reel 1 of 1, 900 ft. (Box 39)
      Moved to Oversized series.
  - Woodshop (1992)
    - 3/4" Umatic, tapes 1-2 of 2, 60 min. (Box 37)
  - Yearbook (1992)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 145 ft. (Box 17)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 145 ft. (Box 17)
  - Untitled (1992)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 200 ft. (Box 17)
  - Untitled (1992)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 220 ft. (Box 17)
      From container: Work Print In-Progress.
  - Untitled (1992)
    Directed by Xavier Marquez.
    - Reversal Original, Super 8mm, reel 1 of 1, 60 ft. (Box 17)
      Photocopy of original box cover in Documentation series.
- Freewater Productions Films: 1993, 31 items
  Contains films made in 1993.
  - Crazy Professor (1993)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 450 ft. (Box 18)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 650 ft. (Box 18)
      From container: Reel 2.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 175 ft. (Box 18)
      From container: Edited Sound.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 250 ft. (Box 18)
  - Duke University Union Promo (1993)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 360 ft. (Box 19)
      From container: Cut Negative.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 110 ft. (Box 19)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reels 1-3 of 4, 750 ft. (Box 18)
      From container: Sound Edits.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 4 of 4, 250 ft. (Box 18)
  - How Educated Am I? An Introspective Look at Education (1993)
    Directed by Evan Berg.
    - VHS, 120 min. (Box 38)
  - Mah at the Hideaway (1993)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 150 ft. (Box 19)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 100 ft. (Box 19)
  - The Guardian (1993)
    Directed by Heather Whitaker. Includes footage of McDonald's Drugstore.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 100 ft. (Box 19)
      From container: Music Outtakes.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 50 ft. (Box 19)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., co., reel 1 of 1, 450 ft. (Box 19)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 280 ft. (Box 19)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., co., reel 2 of 2, 280 ft. (Box 19)
  - The Legend of Herring (1993)
    Directed by Christine Connavo.
    - Negative, 16mm, sd., co., reels 1-4 of 4, 1000 ft. (Box 19)
      Includes 4 reels and several short clips. From container: ECN and Outtakes.
    - Negative, 16mm, sd., co., reels 1-5 of 6, 550 ft. (Box 19)
      Includes 6 reels. From container: Original ECN and Work Print Cut.
    - Negative, 16mm, sd., co., reel 6 of 6, 650 ft. (Box 19)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., co., reel 1 of 1, 600 ft. (Box 19)
    - Betacam SP, 17 min. (Box 35)
  - Untitled (1993)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 100 ft. (Box 19)
      From container: Kate and Seth Practice and ECN.
- Freewater Productions Films: 1994, 32 items
  Contains films made in 1994.
  - All the World's a Stage (1994)
    Directed by Julie Freeman.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 520 ft. (Box 20)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., co., reel 1 of 1, 600 ft. (Box 20)
  - Colonel Anker (1994)
    Directed by Jensen.
    - DAT tape, 60 min. (Box 35)
  - Duke University Union Promo (1994)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reels 1-10 of 10, 750 ft. (Box 20)
      Includes 10 reels of varying sizes. From container: ECN Original and Outtakes.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 180 ft. (Box 20)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 220 ft. (Box 20)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 250 ft. (Box 20)
      From container: Work Print Cut.
  - Rock-A-Bye, Bye Baby (1994)
    Directed by Jenny Lynn. Comedy. Includes shots of Duke Gardens.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 2, 70 ft. (Box 20)
      From container: Original ECN. Reel also includes: The Fortune Teller.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 2 of 2, 70 ft. (Box 20)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 2, 130 ft. (Box 20)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 2 of 2, 80 ft. (Box 20)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 140 ft. (Box 20)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, sd., reel 1 of 1, 140 ft. (Box 20)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 300 ft. (Box 20)
      From container: Edited Work Print. Includes scene entitled Runaway Carraige.
  - Social Leper Boy (1994)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 150 ft. (Box 21)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 50 ft. (Box 21)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 160 ft. (Box 21)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 80 ft. (Box 21)
  - WXDU Trailer (1994)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 150 ft. (Box 21)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 130 ft. (Box 21)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 140 ft. (Box 21)
  - Unfinished Film (1994)
    Directed by Justin Lester.
    - Negative, 16mm, Reversal Original, 16mm, b&w, sd., co., and si., reels 1-9 of 9, 500 ft. (Box 21)
      Includes 9 reels of varying sizes. From container: Sound, Work Print, Negatives.
  - Untitled (1994)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 80 ft. (Box 21)
      From container: Original Negative Head.
- Freewater Productions Films: 1995, 30 items
  Contains films made in 1995.
  - Cable 13 (1995)
    Directed by Wright.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 300 ft. (Box 21)
  - Duet/Biology (1995)
    Directed by Roger Beebe.
    - Negative, 16mm, reels 1-3 of 9, 480 ft. (Box 21)
      From container: Original Negative and Print.
      Edge Number Registers and Director's Cutting Notes moved to Documentation series.
    - Negative, 16mm, reels 4-7 of 9, 180 ft. (Box 21)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 8 of 9, 300 ft. (Box 21)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 9 of 9, 350 ft. (Box 21)
    - Betacam SP, 10 min. (Box 35)
      Tape also includes: Pizza King, The Legend of the Herring.
    - MiniDV, 10 min. (Box 35)
      Tape is entitled: Roger Beebe's Freewater Films (Plus Two). Tape also includes: A Fragmentary History of the 21st Century, Dirty Harry and the Hendersons, Eat Art, Suggs Must Die!, What Boys Want.
  - Kung Fu (1995)
    Directed by Matt Littin.
    - Negative, 16mm, co., reel 1 of 1, 200 ft. (Box 21)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, co., reel 1 of 1, 150 ft. (Box 21)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, co., reels 1-2 of 2, 280 ft. (Box 21)
      Reels also include Positive Print of The Chase.
  - [Freewater Productions Films Workshop Reel] (1995)
    From container: Seth's Workshop.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., b&w, reel 1 of 1, 120 ft. (Box 22)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 180 ft. (Box 22)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 120 ft. (Box 22)
  - The Fortune Teller (1995)
    Directed by Xavier Márquez. Synopsis from container: Three students enroll in a required class and hate the teacher because of his arrogant views.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 70 ft. (Box 22)
      From container: Original ECN. Reel also includes: Rock-A-Bye, Bye Baby.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 100 ft. (Box 22)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 3, 220 ft. (Box 22)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 2 of 3, 240 ft. (Box 22)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 3 of 3, 200 ft. (Box 22)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., b&w, reel 1 of 1, 180 ft. (Box 22)
  - The Purple Prose
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 150 ft. (Box 22)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 350 ft. (Box 22)
  - Toaster (1995)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 140 ft. (Box 22)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 240 ft. (Box 22)
  - Untitled (1995)
    Directed by Ann Trusty.
    - VHS, 120 min. (Box 38)
- Freewater Productions Films: 1996, 71 items
  Contains films made in 1996.
  - A Short Film About Killing (1996)
    Directed by James Hauser.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 210 ft. (Box 24)
      From container: Test Footage and ECN Original.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 1, 200 ft. (Box 24)
  - A-I (1996)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 5, 300 ft. (Box 23)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 2 of 5, 120 ft. (Box 23)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reels 3-5 of 5, 200 ft. (Box 23)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 2, 175 ft. (Box 23)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, b&w, reel 2 of 2, 200 ft. (Box 23)
    - Audio Cassette, 13 min. (Box 23)
      From container: Sound. No reference tone.
  - Another Day, Another Dollar (1996)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 3, 950 ft. (Box 23)
      Edge Receipts moved to Documentation series.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 2 of 3, 950 ft. (Box 23)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 3 of 3, 800 ft. (Box 23)
  - Cinderella's Shoe (1996)
    Directed by Fabrice Lyczba.
    - Negative, 16mm, co., reel 1 of 1, 300 ft. (Box 24)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., co., reel 1 of 1, 300 ft. (Box 24)
    - Betacam SP, 30 min. (Box 37)
      From container: Director's Cut.
  - Eat Art (1996)
    - MiniDV, 60 min. (Box 35)
      Tape is entitled: Roger Beebe's Freewater Films (Plus Two). Tape also includes: Suggs Must Die!, A Fragmentary History of the 21st Century, Dirty Harry and the Hendersons, What Boys Want.
  - Missing Peace (1996)
    Directed by Rebecca Pryce.
    - Negative, 16mm, reels 1-7 of 7, 1750 ft. (Box 24)
      Includes 7 reels of varying sizes. From container: ECN Original.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 280 ft. (Box 24)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 260 ft. (Box 24)
  - Modern Sensibility (1996)
    Directed by Betsy Frederick.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., co., reel 1 of 1, 300 ft. (Box 24)
  - Owls in the Daylight (1996)
    - Negative, 16mm, Positive Print, 16mm, b&w, reels 1-2 of 2, 625 ft. (Box 24)
      From container: Original Negative and Work Print.
  - Richard Krauss (1996)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 250 ft. (Box 24)
      From container: Original Camera Negative and Work Print.
      Work Order moved to Documentation series.
  - Scudder (1996)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 675 ft. (Box 25)
      In container with sound reel 1 of 1 (675 ft.)
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 900 ft. (Box 25)
      In container with sound reel 2 of 2 (1500 ft.)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 675 ft. (Box 25)
      In container with film reel 1 of 1 (675 ft.)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 1500 ft. (Box 25)
      In container with film reel 2 of 2 (900 ft.)
    - Negative, 16mm and Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reels 1-9 of 9, 1500 ft. (Box 25)
      Includes 9 reels of varying sizes, both sound and film reels. From container: Clips, sound and picture.
  - September's Song (1996)
    Directed by John Antonini. Kammerer Award submission.
    - VHS, 120 min. (Box 37)
  - The Bruce Lee/Mean Joe Green Story (1996)
    Directed by Mike Bott.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, sd., co., reel 1 of 1, 80 ft. (Box 25)
  - The Raven (1996)
    Directed by Fabrice Lyczba and Xavier Marquez. Cinematography by Mick McNeely.
    - Negative, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 240 ft. (Box 25)
    - Optical Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 2, 600 ft. (Box 25)
      From container: Final Sound, 14 sec., 1KHZ tone.
    - Optical Sound, 16mm, reel 2 of 2, 550 ft. (Box 25)
    - Betacam SP, 30 min. (Box 37)
      From container: Final edited master.
      Tape also includes: Cinderella's Shoe (Director's Cut).
    - VHS, 30 min. (Box 37)
  - The Sandwich (1996)
    Directed by Rob Koegler.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 1 of 6, 400 ft. (Box 26)
      Edge Number Registers, Camera Reports, and Credits Posters moved to Documentation series.
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reel 2 of 6, 325 ft. (Box 26)
    - Negative, 16mm, b&w, reels 3-6 of 6, 350 ft. (Box 26)
      Includes 4 reels of varying sizes.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 3, 400 ft. (Box 26)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 2 of 3, 400 ft. (Box 26)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 3 of 3, 450 ft. (Box 26)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 3, 250 ft. (Box 26)
      From container: Ambient Filler Sound.
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 2 of 3, 250 ft. (Box 26)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 3 of 3, 300 ft. (Box 26)
    - Magnetic Sound, 16mm, reel 1 of 1, 450 ft. (Box 26)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 1 of 5, 70 ft. (Box 26)
      From container: Work Print Edits and Animation.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 2 of 5, 20 ft. (Box 26)
      From container: Work Print Edits and Beginning Leader.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 3 of 5, 280 ft. (Box 26)
      From container: Work Print Edits and B/W.
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 4 of 5, 350 ft. (Box 26)
    - Positive Print, 16mm, reel 5 of 5, 150 ft. (Box 26)